Guide to the Dorothy Sarnoff papers, 1920-1998.
Sarnoff, Dorothy Papers, 1920-1998
- Series III. Speech Career
  - D. Administrative and Advertising Material
    - Appointment books 1987-1988 (Box 38, Folder 25)
    - Appointment books 1989-1990 (Box 38, Folder 26)
    - Appointment books 1992, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 27)
    - Appointment books 1995, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 28)
    - Appointment books 1998, 2000 (Box 38, Folder 29)
    - Appointment books 2001-2002 (Box 38, Folder 30)
    - Appointment books 2003, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 31)
    - Women's Forum, Inc. membership list 1999 (Box 38, Folder 32)
    - New York Woman 1990 (Box 38, Folder 32)
    - Speech career miscellany (Box 38, Folder 33)
    - invitation, map, ticket, note re event at M/M Richard M. Nixon's home (Western White House) 1972 (Box 38, Folder 34)
    - New York Times, Metropolitan News (Section B [2 copies]) 3/21/1988 (Box 38, Folder 35)
    - Make the Most of your Best, D. S. [uncorrected proof] 1981 (Box 38, Folder 36)
    - Never be Nervous Again, D. S.; uncorrected proofs (2) 1987 (Box 38, Folder 37)
    - Never be Nervous Again, D. S.; standard paperback (2), large format paperback (1) 1987 (Box 39)
    - Never be Nervous Again, D. S.; large format paperback in Chinese (2) 1988 (Box 39)
    - Never be Nervous Again, D. S.; audio book on one cassette 1990 (Box 39)
    - Speech can change your life, D. S.; 1 bound photocopy 1972 (Box 39)
    - Speech can change your life, D. S.; standard paperback 1979 (Box 39)
    - Speech can change your life, D. S.; standard paperback 1981 (Box 39)
  - E. Recordings
    - Video - Dorothy Sarnoff in class, 1975 (Box 26)
    - 1 audio cassette labeled Prime Minister Begin, ca. 1978 (Box 25)
    - 3 audio cassettes relating to Carter Speech preparation, 1979 (Box 25)
    - WLTW interview (Box 39, Audiocassette tr8306)
    - Nervous Scene (Box 39, Audiocassette tr8307)
    - WOR Radio 710 AM interview (Box 39, Audiocassette tr8308)
    - Sarnoff interview (Box 39, Audiocassette tr8309)
    - unidentified (Box 39, Audiocassette tr8)
    - Speak Up, English instruction cassette and magazine for Italian speakers, 1992 (Box 26)
    - Video - Tomorrow Show Tom Snyder, 1979 (Box 26)
    - Video - Dorothy Sarnoff with Bill Buggs, 1982 (Box 26)
    - Video - Today Show, 1982 (Box 26)
    - Video - Today Show, October 1982 (Box 26)
    - Video - Dorothy Sarnoff at Ogilvy & Mather Chicago Secretaries' seminar, 1984 (Box 26)
    - Video - CBS Morning News and Eyewitness News (Box 26)
    - Video - Dorothy Sarnoff clip from The Changing Woman - Women in the Media (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Video - Dorothy Sarnoff in Cleveland (Box 26)
    - Video - Dorothy Sarnoff in Toronto (Box 26)
    - Video - Dorothy Sarnoff on CBS Morning News (Box 26)
    - Video - Dorothy Sarnoff on the Mike Douglas Show (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Video - Dorothy Sarnoff rehearsing then goes in to teaching (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Video - Dorothy Sarnoff teaching (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Video - Dorothy Sarnoff teaching class (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Video - Dorothy Sarnoff working with people in seminar (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Video - Job Interviews (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Video - Nervousness (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Video - Nervousness (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Video - Nervousness (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Video - Not for Women Only - NBC panel discussion with Dorothy Sarnoff (Box 26)
    - Video - Practice tape for voice and sounds (Box 26)
    - Video - Presence is Power (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Video - Presence is Power (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Video - Presence is Power (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Video - Speech Dynamics (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Video - Speech Dynamics Video Teaching (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Video - That's Life Global T.V. (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Video - Titles and Master Slides (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Video - (Box 22)
    - Before and After Facing the Camera (c. 1-VHS, c.2-1" cassette) 1994 (Box 39, Video V-1503)
    - Before and After Speech Dynamics (1-VHS) n.d. (Box 39, Video V-1504)
    - Just in Time: CNNfn (1-VHS) n.d. (Box 39, Video V-1505)
    - Never Be Nervous Again (1-VHS) n.d. (Box 39, Video V-1506)
    - D. S. Principal for a Day (1-VHS) n.d. (Box 39, Video V-1507)
    - D. S.: Sonya live in L.A. (1-VHS) 1988 (Box 39, Video V-1508)
  - F. Books/Cassettes
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Original first draft and notes (1), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Original first draft and notes (2), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Sears School for Young Charmers, Book (Dorothy Sarnoff- Voice and Speech section), 1970 (Box 5, Folder 149)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Book Publicity, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Book Tour material, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Draft (2), ca. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Hardcover copy of book, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Index, notes, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Marketing Program, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Notes, collected articles, ca. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Notes on the Art of Conversation, ca. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Notes, rough draft (1), ca. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Notes, rough draft (2), ca. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Notes, rough draft (1), ca. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Notes, rough draft (2), ca. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Notes, rough draft (3), ca. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Paperback copy of book, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Punchliners and collected quotes, ca. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Some Original Word Drills, ca. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Typescript, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Typescript, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Typescript, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Typescript (1), ca. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Typescript (2), ca. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Typescript (1), ca. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Typescript (2), ca. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Typescript with corrections of Part II - Conversation, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Communicate!, Notes and outlines for unpublished book, ca. 1970-1979 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Chapter 4 notes, Phrase-a-line, ca. 1970-1979 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Quotes, ca. 1970-1979 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Articles on conversation, ca. 1970-1989 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Notes, articles on Interviews, ca. 1970-1989 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Notes, articles on speech, ca. 1970-1989 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Notes, articles on appearance, ca. 1970-1989 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Notes, articles on social nervousness and visual aids, ca. 1970-1989 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Clippings consulted, notes, 1973-1986 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - How To Be A Better You, Outline and notes, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Cassette Script: Conversation, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Cassette Script: How to Prepare a Speech, ca. 1979 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Cassette Scripts: How to Prepare a Speech, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Cassette Scripts: How to Prepare a Speech, How to Control Nervousness, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Cassette Scripts: How to Prepare a Talk or Presentation, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Cassette Script: Material for Anti-Nervousness, ca. 1979 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Cassette Scripts: Scripts and notes, ca. 1979 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Cassette Scripts: Speech Cassettes, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Cassette Scripts: Speech Cassettes, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Cassette Publicity Material, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Cassette Scripts: How to Deliver a Speech, Notes, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Cassette Scripts: How To Control Nervousness, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Cassette Scripts: How to Rehearse and Deliver a Speech, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Cassette Scripts: How to Write a Speech, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Cassette Scripts: Miscellaneous pages & notes, ca. 1979 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Cassette Scripts: Miscellaneous pages & notes, ca. 1979 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Cassette Scripts: Miscellaneous pages & notes, ca. 1979 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Cassette Scripts: Miscellaneous pages & notes, ca. 1979 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Cassette Scripts: Miscellaneous pages & notes, ca. 1979 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Cassette Scripts: Miscellaneous pages & notes, ca. 1979 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Deleted Material From Cassettes, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life Book and cassette set, 1979 (Box 25)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life, Book and cassette set, 1979 (Box 26)
    - Speech Can Change Your Life: Hundreds of Ways to improve your image Cassette set, 1979 (Box 26)
    - Speech Dynamics audio cassette set, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 150)
    - The Dynamics of Being More Dynamic, Typescript, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - The Dynamics of Being More Dynamic, Typescript with notes, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Bound typescript, 1980 (Box 25)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Correspondence, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Appendix I Draft, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Appendix I, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Book outline, ca. 1981 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Chapter 1 Draft, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Chapter 3 Draft, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Chapter 5 Draft, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Chapters 6&7 Draft (1), ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Chapters 6&7 Draft (2), ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Chapter 8 Draft, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Chapter 9 Draft, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Chapter typescripts with notes, ca. 1981 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Control of Nervousness, ca. 1981 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Discarded Pages, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Extra Pages, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Four Exercises, ca. 1981 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Front Matter and Attributes, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Galleys, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Galleys, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Galleys, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Galleys, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Galleys submitted to Doubleday (1), ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Galleys submitted to Doubleday (2), ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Galleys submitted to Doubleday (3), ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Getting Along at the Office draft, ca. 1981 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Miscellaneous Notes, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Miscellaneous section drafts, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Notes, articles on Meetings, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Notes on confidence, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Notes on meeting with President Carter, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Notes on meeting with Prime Minister Begin, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Notes on meetings, ca. 1981 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Typescript pp 2-154, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Make the Most of Your Best, Typescript pp 155-284, ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, General notes, articles, 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Notes, collected articles on public speaking, 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Notes on how to hold meetings, 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Notes, collected articles on media appearances, ca. 1981-1989 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Notes, collected articles for Hot Seat chapter, ca. 1981-1989 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, 2 manuscripts, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Appendix typescript, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Book outline and miscellany, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Cassette Scripts, ca. 1987 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Draft, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Manuscript with table of contents markings (1), 1987 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Manuscript with table of contents markings (2), 1987 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Material edited out of book, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Misc notes, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Part I typescript, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Part II typescript, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Publicity material, press release, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Two Day Program for Eliminating Nervousness, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Typescript, pages 1-151, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Typescript, pages 152- end, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Original working manuscript, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Uncorrected proof paperback, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, 1989 (Box 26)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Cassette set, 1989 (Box 26)
    - Never Be Nervous Again, Cassette set, 1990 (Box 26)
    - Anecdotes for books (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Notes on Familiarization (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Notes on Preparing a Speech (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - The Art of Speaking, Cassette material (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Typescript of unidentified book (1) (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Typescript of unidentified book (2) (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Typescript of unidentified book with notes, Ch 1-7 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Typescript of unidentified book with notes, Ch 8-end (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - G. Memorabilia from Famous People
    - Memorabilia from famous people, 1969-1986 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - [Sheila] (Secretary to Betty Ford) (Box 25, Folder 9)
        Jan. 9, 1975
      - Carter, Rosalynn (Box 25, Folder 9)
        Jun. 29, 1984
      - Carter, Jimmy and Rosalynn (Box 25, Folder 9)
        Oct. 24, 1986
      - Christopher, Warren (Box 25, Folder 9)
        undated
      - Clark, William P. (Box 25, Folder 9)
        Feb. 26, 1982; Nov. 11, 1983
      - Dam, Kenneth W. (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Dole, Elizabeth Hanford (Box 25, Folder 9)
        Apr. 23, 1984
      - McFarlane, Robert C. (Box 25, Folder 9)
        Nov. 15, 1983
      - Nixon, Richard (Box 25, Folder 9)
        Dec. 4, 1972
      - Walters, Barbara (Box 25, Folder 9)
        Mar. 16, 1977 (Telegram)
    - Notes on meeting with Menachem Begin (taken by Milton H. Raymond); Confirmation of telephone message to Menachem Begin, ca. 1979 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Skylab Patches, ca. 1970-1979 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Skylab Memorabilia, 1971-1974 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Bean, Alan L. (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Invitation to Nixon inauguration, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Scrapbook: White House Visit and letter from Menachem Begin, 1978-1979 (Box 25)
      - Avner, Yehuda, Sept. 13, 1978 (Box 25)
      - Begin, Menachem, Nov. 26, 1978 (Box 25)
      - Carter, Jimmy and Rosalynn, Dec. 18, 1980 (Christmas Card) (Box 25)
      - Clough, Susan, Feb. 2, 1978 (Box 25)
      - Epstein, Benjamin R., Aug. 10, 1978 (Box 25)
      - Hendrix, Becky, Sept. 7, 1979 (Box 25)
      - Rafshoon, Gerald M., Jun. 11, 1979; Oct. 3, 1979; Feb. 8. 1980 (Box 25)
      - Sarnoff, Dorothy Letter to Prime Minister Menachem Begin, Aug. [1978] (Box 25)
    - Airforce One badge, 1979 (Box 25)
    - Carter speech prepared for teleprompter, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Practice speech for President Carter, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Small Notebook with notes on meeting with President Carter, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - H. Miscellany
    - Articles and Notes on Stress, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Articles and Notes on Appearance, ca. 1970-1975 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Articles and Notes on How to make a speech, ca. 1970-1975 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Miscellany, 1970-1985 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - General list of Sarnoff collection by Sarnoff to submit for appraisal, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Speechwriting Seminar, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Loose items from scrapbook, 1980-1985 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Series IV. Scrapbooks and Memorabilia
  - Scrapbook - 1940s, 1940-1949 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook - 1940s, 1940-1949 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook - 1940s, 1940-1949 (Box 30)
  - Scrapbook - 1940s, 1940-1949 (Box 30)
  - Scrapbook pages - 1940s, 1940-1949 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook pages - 1940s, 1940-1949 (Box 30)
  - Scrapbook - Hair catching fire during Magdalena, 1948 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook, 1951 (Box 31)
  - Scrapbook, 1952 (Box 31)
  - Scrapbook - 1950s, 1950-1959 (Box 10)
- Series V. Clippings
  - Newsclippings 1930s-1940s, 1930-1949 (Box 2, Folder 23-49)
  - Newsclippings, 1948 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Newsclippings 1950s-1960s, 1950-1969 (Box 3, Folder 1-49)